Hello, my name is Glanju, I am a health
insurance advisor, my hometown is Thrissur. As usual,
today is
a comparison video about health insurance policies.
So if you are searching for health insurance,
try to watch the entire video without skipping it. [Music] Before entering the video,
I have a small piece of advice for you. This is also
a comparison media. It is
something that is said when many names are called. I get
confused when I watch many videos.
So after watching this video,
I felt that this one product is
better or after watching another video,
I felt that that one
product is a little better. When I
ask my friends, my friends say that this policy is better. When I
ask my cousins, they say that
this is a policy that I can take. I have received a claim.
So,
as a personal request, I
try to take the insurance policy that we have planned now, or
what should we say? We keep comparing like this.
In the meantime, if
we get any illness, a
small ECG variation
or something,
we will not be able to take these policies. So, if you are
planning to take health insurance in your mind,
try to take it as soon as possible. Then, study it
slowly and do
comparisons. If you want to
transfer it to another health
insurance policy next year, then my
advice is to
take health insurance as soon as possible and
try not to compare too much. Let's go to the video.
Today, we are
taking the products of four companies for comparison.
One is the plan called ICC Alevate, and the plan
called Super Star by Star Health,
Manipal Sarvottam, and
Ultimate. Why did we
take four products? Now, I
think it has been three or four months since
these products
were launched. After looking at these products,
we will be able to see many unique features.
Then, in today's video,
we will talk about room rent or
ICU.  I am not discussing anything about modern treatment
or ice
treatment or dark
care domiciliary
because in these four insurances, there is
no restriction on the amount of up to sum insured or room. So, I am not repeating it again.
I want to do it in today's video. As
I
said earlier, there are many unique
features in this product.
So, in today's video, that is what
we are discussing today. The first
feature that I will mention is the
coverage. If we
talk about coverage, in this
Icis, there is a rider called Infinity Care,
that is,
an optional rider. This rider is
added once and then it is one time.
We can
use this feature once in a lifetime policy. If we consider
what is the
advantage of Infinity, then
we can say that we can use this feature for any disease, that is,
now.  If I have cancer, stroke
or bone marrow
transplant, I have
taken a policy of 10 lakhs,
but if I have treatment expenses of 50 lakhs
or 1 crore rupees, I
can use that first claim itself. This is a very
unique feature. This same
feature has also been brought in Star Health's Super
Health. It
comes as Unlimited Care. It is an optional
rider. It is a
rider that needs to be added extra. This is also only one time. As mentioned, no matter
how much expense we have,
we
can use it one time for any disease. If this
comes to Manipal Signi, the name of the
rider of this same feature is Anant.
But in Manipal,
they are giving this feature for four diseases as the main one:
cancer, stroke,
bone
marrow transplant, which is a major one, and
cardiac issues. If this comes,
we can use it for four diseases.  Early every year
Early one time No matter how much expense we have incurred,
this one Manipal
Sarvotham is a little more unique. I mean, I have a policy of
10 lakhs for a bone marrow transplant in
my hand, but if
I have an expense of
lakhs or a treatment of 1 crore
rupees for a bone marrow transplant, even if it is a
normal
policy of 10 lakhs, we
can claim for the said four days in the first claim itself. If we
come to Kerala Health, this
option is not available. And
secondly, the bonus is something to
pay attention to. If we
look at ICC, they have brought a rider called a power booster.
As an option, if we consider the benefit of this,
now we usually know that if we have said this
cumulative bonus or bonus, if we
have taken 10 lakhs in all the previous bonuses, then a 100% or  It used to
say 50%, but in the
current policies, they give it as a
net bonus or bonus for infinity.
That is, if we
add this ride called Power Power Boost,
we have a policy of 10 lakhs every year, and when it reaches the
second year, it will be 20,
30, 40, 50 lakhs, and so on. If we
add this ride, that is
how many changes have
come in insurance. So, if we look at Star Health's
Super Health, it has
brought a rider called Super Star Bonus, and the same
features are increasing by 100% every year, and that too is increasing
by 100% infinitely, that is, the 10 is increasing by 20, 30, 40, 50, and so on. If
Manipal comes to the scene, what is
called good benefit? What is a rider
in this?  It is 10X,
meaning if
I have taken a policy of 10 lakhs, after 10 years, what I am doing to
change it to 1 crore is
not a 10X infinite, but
a 10X coverage and it is fixed.
Similarly, if we are
coming to Kerala, as I talked about earlier,
a rider called Infinity Bonus has also been
introduced in this. Rider
means
a coverage that comes as an optional one. When we just
take the policy,
we
can use it after ticking it. So this 100%
increase is also being made in this. Annually,
one of the special features of these is the third and fourth, respectively, of claims. Whether or not a
claim comes,
we will keep getting this bonus.
That is the
biggest special feature of this. As
mentioned, in Care, it also
increases by 100% every year.
That too is infinity.
Another special feature that I saw was
regarding its waiting period. So if you get elevated in ICS, there is
a feature called a jump start.  What is the benefit of it?
Asthma, BP, cholesterol, diabetes,
obesity, all these,
we will get covered for 30 days and all the diseases related to these after
30 days. Other than this, the
waiting period is three years for pre-existing diseases. And as
everyone knows, for some
diseases now, slow growth disease, piles,
kidney, student, etc.,
two years. In all insurance, a
waiting period of two years is
applicable for all these four diseases. Similarly, if Star
Health comes, there is
a ride called Quick Shield. It is
similar to this, say ABCD Plus, that is, asthma,
BP, cholesterol,
diabetes, all these
are covered after 30 days. And
Angiop cases are covered in the policy after one year.
Similarly, in Manipal
Sarva Uttam, there is a similar rider,
its name is Sarathi. In Sarathi, as
mentioned, there is ABCD coverage after
30 days, that is, asthma, BP, cholesterol,
diabetic, etc., we get covered after 30 days, and
similarly, it comes in the ultimate of Care Health, but the
rider has also been brought in. Instant cover. Even
after we have added this instant cover, as mentioned, asthma,
BP, cholesterol, diabetic, obesity,
hypothyroidism, all these are covered after 30 days.
Similarly, angioplasty
cases are also covered after one year.
And another advantage of this is that all these
policies, four
policies, PD, pre-assistant diseases,
all these diseases have a
waiting period of 36 months,
but here a PD
modification has been brought in, which means that
we can reduce our pre-assistant for one year or two years.
Similarly, a
unique feature that we saw next is non-
metal items, which means that now we can
Sometimes in the old policy,
an amount is
taken in the policy, such as cotton, syringe, etc. In
order to cover all these non-metal items, some
riders have been introduced. If you look at ICI, there
is a rider called Claim Protector, so
after adding it,
we will get the expenses covered.
Similarly, in Star
Health, there
is a rider called Consumable Cover, which covers 68 consumer items.
Similarly, in
Manipal Cigna, there is a
rider like this. There is a rider that covers non-medical items, so after taking it,
we will get the expenses covered. In Care
Health's Ultimate,
there is a rider called Claim Shield, so after taking it,
we will get the non-medical items
covered. Similarly, the
next unique
feature is Medical Durable
Items, after adding it, we will get the wheelchair
or what?
We
get insurance coverage for ventilators and infusion pumps.
Now, if we look at IC Elevate,
we
can purchase up to five lakhs. The maximum is five
lakhs. Similarly, if we
look at Star, we are
given a list of nine items. We can buy
these medical durable items
that are on that list. We can use them only once. So, once we buy a
wheelchair,
we
cannot use them again. Similarly, in
Manipal Cigna, we are given 10 items.
We can purchase these durable items.
They say one lakh.
Similarly, if we
look at Kerala, they do not
specifically say that. The
next feature is Pre-N-Post.
As everyone knows,
we
can submit bills up to a certain period before being admitted to the hospital. We can submit
bills up to a certain period after being discharged.  If you
look here, if the pre-end
post comes from ICC, it is
90-150 days, which is a little more,
if it is from Star Health,
it is 90-150, Manipal Signal is 90, if it
comes to Kerala, it is 60 and 90, the deadline for submitting pre-and-
post expenses,
and similarly, there are some extra
features in it.
If you look at the price, based on the CIBIL score,
that is, if
our CIBIL score is above 800, we get a 15%
discount, and if it is
above 750, we get a 7% discount. If we are
NRI customers, we
get 25%,
but the maximum discount for
us is 32%, and
we can use it all together. Similarly, if
we do it one month before, as mentioned, during the renewal time, we
get a 25% discount. There is a
maternity coverage after two years.
After that, maternity
expenses are also covered. If we
look at Super Star, we
have an option called Free Sure Age, which means that
our premium is locked. Now,
I think this Star Health
product is a product that has been copied from all the companies. This is the same feature that
was in Niwapi's Asper.
They have also brought a feature here that allows us to lock the premium until the age of 50.
Similarly, the shield,
which means that after we add this rider, when we
add Bhava's spouse,
we will not have a waiting period.
Now, if they
have any illnesses, the cover is already covered in advance. Now,
sometimes, a two-year
waiting period was said. For some
illnesses, we will get all that
favored. After adding Future Shield, then the
maternity expenses are also covered.
After two years, maternity expenses are
covered. And the
big option in this is that
we can take the premium for five years together.  If we
take it for a year, we
get a discount of about 16 percent,
but if we take it as EMI,
that discount will not be available to us.
Similarly, if we
look at Manipal, one of the features that is
called surplus
benefit is a
special feature that I have heard. I have heard that there is a
surplus benefit,
that is, if I
have taken 10 lakhs from day one to day one, I have a ride rail that gives me
2X coverage right from day one.
Similarly, if we
make a payment one month in advance for renewal, we
get a discount of about two percent.
Then when we come to Kerala, we
see some extra features, that is, we get a
refund, that is, if we do not make
any claims for five years, we get back the first year premium in the sixth year.
And similarly, as
mentioned, we have
an option to choose the five-year premium together.
It is said that when choosing a five-year policy,
the rate is terrible and the
premium is very low. If you do this five-year
policy together, then
similarly, if you renew within 31 days to 60
days, you are
given a discount of about 5 percent. Similarly, in Kerala, if you do it
before the claim, you are
given a discount of about 2.5 percent. Then there is
a
benefit called a tensor multiplier, that is, if we take the five-year
policy together, if we have a
coverage of 10 lakhs,
we can use it together for the first claim of 50 lakhs.
So, a tensor
multiplier benefit has been
introduced. In all this, in Care
Health, similarly,
one thing that we are all waiting for is how is the premium? If you
look at the premium, if you are 65 or 60 years old, if you
come under ICC, then the
rate in Kerala is
around ₹47630. If we do not have
any rider, it is close to 10
lakhs. Similarly, in
Star Health,  ₹59254
without any rider, the
rate is a little
higher in Star. If you look at it comparatively,
similarly if you look at Manipal Sena, it
comes to ₹32610. For 10 lakhs, the
annual premium is increasing in this age category. Pay
attention to that. Similarly, if you
look at Care Health, the premium comes to us
around ₹38237. For 10 lakhs, if you
look at this same 35-30 age category, the premium
comes to us around 10824. If you look at
Star Healthy without adding any riders, it
comes to 19127. If Manipal
Signal is
₹9705, if it is Care Health, it comes to 11260.
I think Star Health
has a little higher rate.
Anyway, try to choose policies that are in accordance with our interest and
try to use it for study purposes. As I
said in the beginning, rather than making excessive
comparisons, buy a health
insurance as soon as possible.
Try to take out insurance,
then we can do comparisons and
transfer our waiting period to another company during the extreme renewal time. So,
try to take it out as soon as possible.
Similarly, to know more about insurance and
to take a policy, its WhatsApp number is
given below, so
you can send a message to it.
Thank you, dear friends. If you
like the videos of Katukumani, you should join us.